

CONTACT

- moel-huijskens.azurewebsites.net
- ✓ roelh96@gmail.com
- P Den Haag, Ypenburg
- Linkedin [link]

SKILLS

- Python
- R
- SQL/Postgres/Mongo/Redis
- Software Engineering
- Azure
- Linux
- Statistics
- Ansible
- Presenting

LANGUAGES

- Dutch (Mother Language)
- English (Fluent)

Liever de Nederlandse versie? Zie: [link]

ROEL HUIJSKENS

SOFTWARE/DATA/DEVOPS ENGINEER

PROFILE

Highly motivated Software/DevOps Engineer with a strong background in applied statistics. Acquired substantial practical experience implementing data analytics tooling solutions in an organization with strict regulatory standards. My most productive days are spent tackling complex problems by implementing maintainable and flexible solutions. I highly value knowledge sharing within organizations and constructive collaboration. Always curious and learning new technical skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Stedin

2024 - PRESENT

Datalake Platform Engineer

- Azure Databricks
- Apache Airflow
- Azure Devops
- Terraform

APG Asset Management

Devops Engineer

2022 - 2024

- Developed and maintained tools for building data analytics applications using R/Python on Posit and custom APIs (e.g. an interface for the Bloomberg Data License platform).
- Assisted the business in implementing best practices for software/application development, including CI/CD and testing.
- Co-created a chatbot (OpenAI + RAG) to answer questions regarding the documentation of our team.
- Co-owner of the Python community, promoting best practices and knowledge sharing.

Createment

2020 - 2022

IT Trainee

- Completed an extensive 2-month bootcamp focusing on software design patterns, Java, Scrum, and data modeling.
- Implemented a process for delivering databases to business users.
- Assisted users in building and deploying their Qlik, R, Python applications, and Alteryx workflows.

CERTIFICATIONS

Azure

- Azure Fundamentals [Link]
- Azure Al Fundamentals [Link]
- Azure Data Scientist Assoc [Link]
- Azure Data Engineer Assoc [Link]

DeepLearning.ai

- Machine Learning [Link]
- Deep Learning [Link]

Alteryx

• Alteryx Designer Core [Link]

Datacamp

• Python Developer [Link]

Scrum.org

• Prof Scrum Master I [Link]

Statistics Netherlands (CBS)

2019 - 2020

Research Intern

- Completed my research master's thesis on non-probability sampling in official statistics.
- Completed the European Master in Official Statistics (EMOS) program.

EDUCATION

Master Applied Statistics

2018-2020

Utrecht University

- Selective Research Master with a strong focus on statistical methodology
- Thesis: Correcting Selectivity of Non-probability Samples by Means of Sample Matching
- · Graduated Cum Laude
- · Key Courses:
 - Mathematical Statistics
 - Multivariate Statistics
 - Statistical Learning (ML)
 - Statistical Computing with R
 - Bayesian Statistics

See my website for more info

Bachelor Psychology

2015-2018

VU Amsterdam

- Bachelor program psychology with a specialization in statistics/research methodology and behavioral genetics.
- Thesis: Power Analysis of Detecting G-E Correlation using the Classical Twin Model Extended with Polygenic Scores (awarded best thesis of my cohort: certificate [Link]).
- GPA: 8
- · Key Courses:
 - Statistics
 - R programming
 - Psychometrics
 - Research Methodology
 - Behavioural Genetics

See my website for more info